<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[A starter blog demonstrating what Gatsby can do.]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 10:40:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Expression Expedition]]></title><description><![CDATA[You are a bioinformatics sleuth tasked with uncovering the mysteries of gene expression in a groundbreaking study. Your mission begins with…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Expression Expedition/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Expression Expedition/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You are a bioinformatics sleuth tasked with uncovering the mysteries of gene expression in a groundbreaking study. Your mission begins with a dataset containing gene expression levels from two different experimental conditions: &quot;Treatment A&quot; and &quot;Control.&quot; Your goal is to identify genes that exhibit significant differential expression between these conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using whatever method works for you, download the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;csv&lt;/code&gt; file below and find the top 5 genes that are differentially expressed the most (have the highest log fold change).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/main/question_generation/expression_expedition_data.csv&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Heartbeat Hero]]></title><description><![CDATA[You are a cardiologist with a clinic full of patients, one of which you think has Long QT Syndrome. For each patient, you have a list of…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Heartbeat Hero/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Heartbeat Hero/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You are a cardiologist with a clinic full of patients, one of which you think has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nhlbi.nih.gov/health/long-qt-syndrome&quot;&gt;Long QT Syndrome&lt;/a&gt;. For each patient, you have a list of their cardiac events (PQRST) and how long they spend in each one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;csv&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-csv&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-csv&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token value&quot;&gt;P&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token value&quot;&gt;34.2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token value&quot;&gt;Q&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token value&quot;&gt;22.1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token value&quot;&gt;R&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token value&quot;&gt;45.6&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token value&quot;&gt;S&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token value&quot;&gt;12.3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token value&quot;&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token value&quot;&gt;34.5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token value&quot;&gt;P&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token value&quot;&gt;34.3&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token value&quot;&gt;...etc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to find the patient with the longest average QT interval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/raw/main/question_generation/heartbeat_hero_data.zip&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Drunk Dilemma]]></title><description><![CDATA[You are investigating if people who drink have a higher likelihood of taking drugs; you have a collected data from a survey and have the…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Drunk Dilemma/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Drunk Dilemma/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You are investigating if people who drink have a higher likelihood of taking drugs; you have a collected data from a survey and have the table of data below - but you need to statistically test if there is a correlation between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculate the p-value using the appropriate test and submit the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/main/question_generation/drunk_dilemma.csv&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Difficult Deltas]]></title><description><![CDATA[You are trying to perform a delta delta CT analysis on a dataset. Below is the dataset of the CT values of the housekeeper gene and the gene…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Difficult Deltas/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Difficult Deltas/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You are trying to perform a delta delta CT analysis on a dataset. Below is the dataset of the CT values of the housekeeper gene and the gene of interest under control and treated conditions. You need to find the mean delta delta CT value of the gene of interest in treated samples compared to control samples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/main/question_generation/difficult_deltas.csv&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Monkey Masses]]></title><description><![CDATA[You are a researcher studying the effect of exercise on monkeys. You have two groups of monkeys - one that has been given access to an…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Monkey Masses/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Monkey Masses/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You are a researcher studying the effect of exercise on monkeys. You have two groups of monkeys - one that has been given access to an outdoor gym area and one that hasn&apos;t. In the dataset below, you are given the lean muscle mass of each monkey in each group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do the monkeys that have access to the gym have more lean muscle mass than those that don&apos;t? Provide a p-value from the appropriate test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/raw/main/question_generation/monkey_masses.csv&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Performance Pulse]]></title><description><![CDATA[You are conducting an experiment with drivers, measuring their pulse rate at different speeds. You have the pulse rates of 100 drivers at…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Performance Pulse/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Performance Pulse/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You are conducting an experiment with drivers, measuring their pulse rate at different speeds. You have the pulse rates of 100 drivers at different speeds. You need to create a linear regression model for testing if speed has an effect on heart rate, and provide the p-value of the speed coefficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/main/question_generation/performance_pulse.csv&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stressful Surveys]]></title><description><![CDATA[You've performed a survey on the stress levels of PhD students in your department. Below is the dataset of the stress levels of students…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Stressful Surveys/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Stressful Surveys/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You&apos;ve performed a survey on the stress levels of PhD students in your department. Below is the dataset of the stress levels of students before along with some lifestyle questions. How many students reported above average stress levels (&gt;3) but below average sleep levels (&amp;#x3C;3)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/main/question_generation/stressful_surveys.csv&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sugar Squeeze (Part 1)]]></title><description><![CDATA[You are conducting a study on health inequalities - you've recorded the weights (in kg) of 100 people as split by the daily amount of sugar…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Sugar Squeeze (pt1)/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Sugar Squeeze (pt1)/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You are conducting a study on health inequalities - you&apos;ve recorded the weights (in kg) of 100 people as split by the daily amount of sugar they consume, split into 5 groups. Is there any evidence to suggest that sugar consumption has an effect of weight? You will need to submit the p-value from the appropriate statistical test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/raw/main/question_generation/sugar_squeeze_pt1.csv&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sugar Squeeze (Part 2)]]></title><description><![CDATA[You are conducting another study on health inequalities - you've recorded the weights (in kg) of 100 people as split by the daily amount of…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Sugar Squeeze (pt2)/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Sugar Squeeze (pt2)/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You are conducting another study on health inequalities - you&apos;ve recorded the weights (in kg) of 100 people as split by the daily amount of sugar they consume - but this time you have 5 groups &lt;em&gt;each&lt;/em&gt; for the amount of fructose and the amount of sucrose they consume, totaling 25 groups. This time, find if there is a significant effect on weight for the amount of sucrose, fructose, or the combination of the two on weights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/raw/main/question_generation/sugar_squeeze_pt2.csv&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tricky Tests]]></title><description><![CDATA[You have a master's student who is conducting a simple t-test comparing two groups you know to be different, however no matter what the…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Tricky Tests/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Tricky Tests/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You have a master&apos;s student who is conducting a simple t-test comparing two groups you know to be different, however no matter what the student does, they always get strange p-values. You remember that a t-test requires the assumption of normality of the samples - so you get one of the groups to perform the correct statistical test to see if the test is appropriate. Given the dataset, find the p-value of the correct normality test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/main/question_generation/tricky_tests.csv&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wicked Westerns]]></title><description><![CDATA[You are conducting a western blot detecting the upregulation of peroxiredoxin (PRDX) under certain conditions. Below is the dataset of the…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Wicked Westerns/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Wicked Westerns/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You are conducting a western blot detecting the upregulation of peroxiredoxin (PRDX) under certain conditions. Below is the dataset of the intensity of 5 control samples and 5 treated samples. You need to find the mean ratio of PRDX up regulation in treated samples compared to control samples. Remember to include the housekeeper gene as a control!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/main/question_generation/wicked_westerns.csv&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Challenging Curves]]></title><description><![CDATA[You have some data but don't have a good statistical way of analysing a fit, so need to resort to a curve fitting method. Below is the…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Challenging Curves/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Challenging Curves/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You have some data but don&apos;t have a good statistical way of analysing a fit, so need to resort to a curve fitting method. Below is the dataset of the x and y values of a curve. You know the data fits a curve of the form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
b * a^x + c
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you don&apos;t know the values of a, b, and c. Find these values!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/main/question_generation/challenging_curves.csv&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nebulous Nucleotides]]></title><description><![CDATA[You are a geneticist trying to find a common block of nucleotides in a set of DNA sequences. You have the sequences for 10 patients, and…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Nebulous Nucleotides/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Nebulous Nucleotides/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You are a geneticist trying to find a common block of nucleotides in a set of DNA sequences. You have the sequences for 10 patients, and need to find the patient with the most number of the sequence &quot;ACGTGCA&quot;. In the case of a tie, give both patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/main/question_generation/nebulous_nucleotides.zip&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Response Riddle]]></title><description><![CDATA[You are conducting an experiment on drug efficacy effecting the response of a biomarker when the drug is administered. You have the response…]]></description><link>https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Response Riddle/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsbystarterblogsource.gatsbyjs.io/Response Riddle/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;You are conducting an experiment on drug efficacy effecting the response of a biomarker when the drug is administered. You have the response of 100 patients before and after the drug was given. You need to test whether or not the drug has changed the distribution these values were taken from using the appropriate statistical test. Provide the p-value of the test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stmball/dimen-ctf/main/question_generation/response_riddle.csv&quot;&gt;Download the dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>